You said you think you visited hell.
>> I know I did. And it was more real than
anything I've experienced. It was the
most amount of fear I'd ever felt in my
life. My body was contorted. It was
doing things that the human body
shouldn't do. [music]
>> Do you think you were possessed? Because
subsequently, you've had several
exorcisms.
>> Yes. The things that are happening are
just undeniable.
>> What happened?
>> I'll tell you what I experienced.
>> Just before we get into all of that, you
have lived a remarkable life. I was in a
US Navy, went to Iraq, Haiti,
Afghanistan, and done some insane
missions. I mean, you learn a lot of
critical life lessons, but there's
another side, too. I [music] mean, you
get addicted to those type of
environments. Adrenaline.
>> And after your CIA contracting role, you
moved to Medlin, Columbia.
>> Yeah. It was probably the most dangerous
thing I'd ever done.
>> Did you get involved in the drug dealing
networks?
>> Yes. I never really dealt. It was more
setting up the network, figuring out who
the players are that gave me the rush.
There's not very many people that can
pull some like that off. But then this
guy Freddy, he said, "The police [music]
were after me." They had planted a bug
in the light fixture outside of my door.
And then they
>> You now have built one of the biggest
podcasts on planet Earth.
>> Yes, but my show will not appear in
popular podcasts because it's something
that I was saying a long time ago. It
had to do with
>> That is very [ __ ] weird. Do you think
podcasters are being compromised by
guests being planted on their shows or
in other ways?
>> Yes. Here's one example. Trump
administration crushed it in the
election cycle, right? Really utilized
the podcast. They saw the power of it.
It was a great tactic and so I think
that [music] they have people inside of
all the platforms that we use and this
has happened to me because one time I
had a guy come on and we can talk about
that.
>> And you endorsed Trump before the
election.
>> I wanted him to win. Have you changed
your opinion on Trump now?
>> Oh yeah, for a multitude of reasons. I
probably shouldn't be satisfied.
>> Before this episode starts, I have a
small favor to ask you. Two months ago,
61% of the people that watch this
channel weren't subscribed. We're now
down to 58%. My goal is 50%. So, if
you've ever liked any of the videos
we've made on this channel, if you like
this channel, can you do me a small
quick favor and hit the subscribe
button? It helps this channel more than
you know. And the bigger the channel
gets, the more we can invest in bringing
you even better guests. Thank you and
enjoy this episode. [music]
>> [singing]
>> Sean Ryan, you have lived a remarkable
life for so many different reasons. Um,
I feel like you've lived several
different lives as well, dare I say. But
for anybody that might not be familiar
with your smash hit show and your
incredible journey through the military,
can you give me a a topline on the
career that you've had before you got
into podcasting for those that might not
know? Yeah, joined the US Navy. It I
think I enlisted at age 17, went
straight to into the Navy Seal program,
went to BUDS, went to SEAL teammate,
spent 5 and a half years in the Navy,
and then left that, became a real estate
agent. I had read a book by Donald Trump
way back then on this is it, how to get
rich. It inspired me to become an
entrepreneur and failed miserably.
[laughter] So then I looked at
government contracting, started
contracting for central intelligence
agencies, started a small state
department gig, got picked up for the
CIA contract, did that through
Blackwater, then jumped over to a
company called Socked and then uh wound
up getting picked up direct contractor
for the agency of No Middleman.
>> And you said that you wanted to be a
Navy Seal. Now, for for international
audiences that might not know what a
Navy Seal is relative to just like being
in the army, what is the distinction?
>> A Navy seal stands for sea, air, and
land. So, you operate in the sea, air,
and the land. It's uh special
operations. So, it is uh one of the most
prolific special operations units in the
world. You go through a training
pipeline that's a couple years long. you
go through buds, which if you make it um
without getting hurt or without getting
rolled back, that's 6 months. I didn't
make it without rolling back. So, I
think I spent about 9 months there. Then
you go to jump school. Then you go to
SQT SEAL qualification training, which
is kind of where they turn you into
I guess I shouldn't say they turn you
into a special operator, but but that's
the the final school. Then you get your
SEAL trident and then you spend another
year or two, year and a half training at
your SEAL team before you ever even get
the opportunity to to to deploy uh for
the country. Diving, jumping, land
warfare, demolition, small unit tactics,
lots of time in a kill house, lots of
time in land warfare, all different uh
operational environments, desert,
winter, jungle, you name it, we're in
it. Is it equivocal to the SAS which is
like the British version of the special
operations team?
>> I would say yeah SAS or SPS.
>> Okay. And you must have seen some pretty
horrific interesting
unforgettable things while you were on
those tours of duties around the world.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Oper.
The first thing I ever saw uh that was
that that that
was warfareish. It wasn't really hot. I
thought it was hot at the time, but uh
2004 we went to Haiti when Aristid got
pulled out of power. It was the first
time I'd really seen true poverty. And
uh I don't know if you've ever been
there, but I mean, you know, the sewage
goes right into the streets. All the
prisoners had broken out. We there were
dead bodies floating around the water,
bullet holes everywhere.
Every once in a while, I'd see a car on
fire. I mean, it was just vast chaos. It
really wasn't anything compared to what
I would see later on. But uh [sighs] but
that was the first place. And then
Afghanistan uh we went there after
Operation Red Wings uh happened. That
was uh the biggest loss in SEAL team
history at the time.
>> What was Operation Red Wings?
>> Have you ever seen the movie Lone
Survivor?
>> No.
>> Okay. There was a a sniper element on a
mountaintop that was that was
surveilling a town that had a highv
value terrorist in in there. And um the
sniper hide was compromised by a goat
herder. Goat herder went back to town
and told everybody what he had seen and
then and then they ambushed the element
up there. Helicopters went down and then
there was one guy that survived it. And
so it was it was the biggest loss ever
in Seal Team history at the time. That
happened in on June 28th and I think we
were there by late late September, early
October, I believe, is when we were
there. We did some uh hit some targets,
but they were pretty much all dry holes.
Grabbed a couple of prisoners. Um stuff
like that. And then we actually went
home early. And then I went to Iraq.
Well, I went to Iraq. My platoon went
home. I decided I wanted to get out at
that point. Uh it just for me it wasn't
really what it was uh what I thought it
was going to be.
>> What was it?
>> I thought it would be a lot more combat.
I wanted to go out every night and do
the job, do direct actions,
do CQB, do sniper stuff, whatever. I
just wanted to work. And uh we weren't
getting that in Afghanistan. It was few
and far between. This was 05 time frame
and 0506
time frame. I can't remember what
happened. Uh but the elections were
dragging on and so I had a OIC which is
kind of like the leader of a of a SEAL
platoon. He had found a way to farm us
out to conventional units that were
getting hit were getting hit on supply
routes with with roadside bombs, uh
suicide bombers, stuff like that. And so
we would attach into these conventional
units and train them up. Hey, this is
how you this is how you run
surveillance. This is how you come up
with a mission basically. And we would
teach them everything from how to plan
the mission to how to set up a sniper
hide, how to shoot, how to insert, how
to Xfill, uh how to position all the
different teams. And then we would go
out there. We would take them with us
and uh hunt the people that were killing
our guys. And every time we went out,
we'd
we had killed the bad guys, uh, the
terrorists within within 24 hours of
being out there. And then we move on to
the next unit and that was my last
deployment.
>> When you came back from the SEAL team,
were you a different man?
>> Definitely.
>> In what way were you changed?
>> A lot of ways. you learn uh a lot of
critical life lessons uh in the SEAL
teams and being in environments like
that and your personal drive just goes
through the roof. Uh what you realize
that you can accomplish as a human being
uh is far more than I think what the
normal person thinks. [snorts] your
ability to to work in stress uh in
extreme stress uh goes through the roof.
There's another side too. I mean you get
addicted to adrenaline. You get addicted
to
those type envir of environments. You
succumb to the culture that comes with
that which is a lot of drinking,
fighting, all those things.
>> So you're in the Navy Seals.
>> Mhm.
You contract with the CIA for a while
and then I guess the other, you know,
pretty tremendous accomplishment is you
now have built one of the biggest
podcasts on planet earth where you
interview people just like I do here.
That is correct. Do you think podcasters
are being compromised by sort of guests
being planted? Yes.
I have no proof, but yes. And in a in a
couple of different ways. So here's one
example.
Not just podcast. Let's go influencers,
not just podcasters.
So Trump administration
[sighs and gasps]
crushed it in the elections in the
election cycle, right? Different
podcasts, they they really utilized the
podcast. They saw the power of it. They
utilized it and uh it was a great
tactic. And then afterwards, you know, I
think a lot of podcasters and
influencers, they felt powerful because,
you know, the they got close to the
president, they got close to the
administration. And if you saw what
happened, you know, do you remember the
ep the first Epstein file release?
>> Yes.
>> When they had all these people show up
and they're holding up the binders and
[ __ ] you know, they did not understand
that the minute that happened, they were
captured.
>> Who was
>> the everybody that was in those
pictures?
>> Oh, okay. Yeah. they can no longer be a
freethinker because maybe they are a
freethinker but the appearance that they
just gave off is that they are in a
tribe you know and they were smart to do
this and and I've had several invites I
always turn it down because no I don't I
don't know I'm not doing that
>> invites to where invites to wherever
>> the white house
>> football games the white house this that
you know public events where you'll be
seen where you'll be photographed where
it looks like everybody's on
>> one team and we're all having a party
and we're all friends and all this [ __ ]
You know, that's a way to capture what
you're doing without you even realizing
it and showing the world, hey, look, we
have we have Steven. We've got him.
We've got pictures of him holding
binders up. We've got pictures of him at
dinners with us. He's on our team. And
maybe you didn't want that, but you were
so fixated on being close to power
>> that you didn't even realize it was
happening. M. And now those those people
those people are all captured. It feels
like once in a lifetime stuff. Hey, we
want you to come, you know, ride on Air
Force One, ride on Marine One, do this,
do this with us, do this.